Whether you have a professional or individual selling account, you're eligible to enroll in FBA.
You can use FBA to store your products in Amazon's fulfillment centers and let us pick, pack and
ship your FBA orders.
We'll also handle returns and provide customer service on your behalf for these orders.
With FBA, your items become eligible for Prime Shipping, meaning Amazon Prime customers can benefit
from free two-day service.
And all Amazon customers can get free shipping on eligible orders.
This is a great way to maximize
exposure and sales in the Amazon store.
Here's how FBA works.
First, you'll register for FBA and decide
which products you'd like to send to a fulfillment center.
Note that many but not all products are
eligible for FBA, even if you're approved to fulfill orders for these products yourself.
Once you've
determined which products you'd like to send to Amazon and checked that they're eligible, you'll
create your first FBA shipment.
This includes prepping, labeling and packing your products, printing
box labels, and if you're sending pallet shipments confirming carrier and pallet information.
Note
that proper preparation, packaging and labeling can help ensure your products get transported
safely and securely to the fulfillment center.
This will help Amazon make your items available
to customers more quickly.
When you're ready, send your shipment off to one or more of Amazon's
fulfillment centers as needed.
After a fulfillment center receives your products, customers can
begin purchasing your FBA offers in the Amazon store.
You'll pay fulfillment fees for each unit
that's picked, packed and shipped to customers from an Amazon fulfillment center.
These costs
vary depending on each item's size, weight and category.
You may also encounter additional fees
for storing and managing your inventory.
We'll pack and ship all FBA orders on your behalf and
handle both customer service and returns for them.
To put it simply, you sell and Amazon handles the
rest.
If a customer returns an item, they'll send it back to the fulfillment center that shipped
their order and it will be subject to the FBA customer returns policy.
The fulfillment center
will evaluate the items and return those still in sellable condition to your inventory.
Some
product categories may incur an FBA returns processing fee.
We recommend using the revenue
calculator to estimate these and other FBA costs.
Ready to learn more about FBA?
Registered sellers
can review the FBA product eligibility guide in Seller Central.